Now we are going to go over some measuring rules.
This is called an eyebrow map.
Ok.?
It's called a shaping map.
A couple of things you want to learn.
First of all just take your stick or even your eyebrow brush, something with a straight line and what you want to do is measure from the inside of the nose, I mean, excuse me, the outside of the nose, hold the stick straight up.
You're drawing imaginary lines, ok.?
That's where the inside of her eyebrow is going to start, right here where this line is.
That's the inside of her eyebrow, which is where it is naturally so that's good.
Then you want to take the same space from her nose and draw an imaginary line again follow it to the outside corner of her eye and that's where the outside of her eyebrow will end.
If your eyebrow ends short of that naturally then that's fine, don't make it any shorter, but you want to let that, your fine, fine few hairs end up, that's a natural line, that's your map.
Ok.?
So I've got my inside starting, my outside ending, now your arch right in the middle of your eyebrow, is where your arch should be, the highest point of your eyebrow.
When you're looking straight forward, where the pupil of your eye is, go ahead and open your eye, where the pupil of her eye is I want to hold this straight up above and that's where the highest part of her arch is going to be.
So now I've created, that's all natural lines, no matter what your face shape is.
So now I have actually created an eyebrow map.
Now that I know the shape that I need to take I'm going to kind of embed this in my memory, in my brain, or if you need to remeasure as you go along that's fine.
So now I know where the shape that I want her eyebrows to be.